Kayla Glick

((815) 757-0118

🔀 kaylaglick12@gmail.com

kayla-glick.github.io

Raleigh, NC

Skills & Knowledge

Programming Languages

Ruby | Go | JavaScript | TypeScript SQL | HTML | CSS/SCSS

Libraries & Frameworks

Ruby on Rails | React | Twirp | Node.js Bootstrap

Software Design Principles

System Design | Data Modeling | Project Management | REST & RPC APIs | UI/UX | **Event Stores**

Other Tools

Git | Figma | Heroku | Kafka | Datadog Sentry Docker

Education

College of Charleston, SC

2018

B.S. Computer Science

Mathematics Minor

Other Interests

Fantasy World-Building

PC & Tabletop Gaming

Architecture & Interior Design

Music & Composition

Food & Cooking

Coffee

Summary

Detail-oriented senior software engineer with 9 years of experience leading and working with teams to design, build, and deploy web applications at scale with a focus on UI/UX, performance, and observability. Seeking senior+ roles with opportunities to lead teams and build beautiful interfaces and experiences for users.

Experience

(7) GitHub

Senior Software Engineer

Aug 2022 - Present

Remote

Ruby on Rails | Go | TypeScript | React | Protobufs | Kafka

- Build new tools and services in GitHub's monolith and microservices connected by Kafka event stores and integrated with Zuora and Azure.
- Lead initiatives to create a new billing UX and underlying billing platform as well as other projects across the billing domain.
- Model for both relational and non-relational data at enterprise scale on top of MySQL and Cosmos DB.
- Facilitate team retros and discussions to improve how the team works together socially and technically.
- Train and mentor others through pairing, discussions, and presentations.

Outchie

Senior Software Engineer II

Nov 2021 - Jul 2022

Remote

Ruby on Rails | React | TypeScript | GraphQL

- Architected the workflows, services, and underlying relational data models supporting Dutchie's in-house payments service, Dutchie Pay.
- Drafted engineering project blueprints from product specifications and design mock-ups, and consult on blueprints from other teams.
- Worked with product & design to manage project boards, timelines, and allocate developer resources.
- Drove incident response and managed releases and deployments for the payments team using Heroku Enterprise.
- Mentored and provided guidance to other members of the engineering org.
- Developed a new platform for accepting online credit card payments with Rails, GraphQL, and React.

Senior Software Engineer I Remote

Mar 2021 - Nov 2021



Medical University of SC

Senior Web Developer

Jan 2020 - Feb 2021

Charleston, SC / Remote

Ruby on Rails | JavaScript | HTML/CSS | Bootstrap

- Led multiple projects to overhaul our front-end UX, including implementing Bootstrap and re-designing multiple portions of our applications.
- Improved application performance by implementing caching and query optimization.
- Collaborated with stakeholders to plan new features, sprints and releases.

Web Developer

Oct 2018 - Dec 2019

Remote

Intern Web Developer

Jun 2015 - Sep 2018

Charleston, SC

Special Projects



🔯 wowsims.github.io

Admin & Open-Source Developer

Oct 2022 - Present

Go | TypeScript | JSX | Protobufs | Web Assembly

- Collaborate with a community of open-source contributors to build web tools that simulate World of Warcraft gameplay in order to help players make decisions about how to prepare and play their characters.
- Over 3000 total commits with over 100,000 lines of code changed.
- Incrementally redesigned the entire WoWSims UI over the course of a year based on concept designs from another contributor.
- Provide updates, troubleshooting, and manage relations with our player community in our Discord server across multiple external servers.
- Lead developer on WoWSims Season of Discovery.